Title,Link,Content,Sentiment Score,Image Link,Publication Year,Keywords,Entities,Section
The Secret History of Gun Rights: How Lawmakers Armed the N.R.A.,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/30/us/politics/nra-congress-firearms.html,"Long before the National Rifle Association tightened its grip on Congress, won over the Supreme Court and prescribed more guns as a solution to gun violence — before all that, Representative John D. Dingell Jr. had a plan.

First jotted on a yellow legal pad in 1975, it would transform the N.R.A. from a fusty club of sportsmen into a lobbying juggernaut that would enforce elected officials’ allegiance, derail legislation behind the scenes, redefine the legal landscape and deploy “all available resources at every level to influence the decision making process.”

“An organization with as many members, and as many potential resources, both financial and influential within its ranks, should not have to go 2d or 3d Class in a fight for survival,” Mr. Dingell wrote, advocating a new aggressive strategy. “It should go First Class.”

To understand the ascendancy of gun culture in America, the files of Mr. Dingell, a powerful Michigan Democrat who died in 2019, are a good place to start. That is because he was not just a politician — he simultaneously sat on the N.R.A.’s board of directors, positioning him to influence firearms policy as well as the private lobbying force responsible for shaping it.",0.2047979797979798,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/30/multimedia/00nra-files-cgbv/00nra-files-cgbv-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['rifle', 'congress', 'supreme court', 'gun violence —', 'john d. dingell jr.', 'n.r.a', 'fusty club', 'officials ’ allegiance', 'derail legislation', 'legal landscape', 'deploy “', 'available resources', 'decision making process. ” “', 'potential resources', '3d class', 'mr. dingell', 'new aggressive strategy', 'class.', 'gun culture', 'america', 'mr. dingell', 'michigan democrat', 'good place', 'politician —', 'n.r.a.', '’ s board', 'firearms policy']","[('the National Rifle Association', 'ORG'), ('Congress', 'ORG'), ('the Supreme Court', 'ORG'), ('John D. Dingell Jr.', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('1975', 'DATE'), ('N.R.A.', 'ORG'), ('2d', 'CARDINAL'), ('3d', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dingell', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('America', 'GPE'), ('Dingell', 'PERSON'), ('Michigan', 'GPE'), ('Democrat', 'NORP'), ('2019', 'DATE'), ('N.R.A.', 'ORG')]",Politics
The Legacy Dilemma: What to Do About Privileges for the Privileged?,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/30/us/politics/legacy-admissions-college-alumni.html,"Like Ms. James-Chakraborty, students and alumni of many colleges and universities — not just ultra-elite ones — are now wrestling with the practice of legacy admissions, a debate with far broader implications after the Supreme Court last month gutted race-based admissions programs and forced colleges to reconsider their criteria for accepting students.

It has sparked some bracing introspection and complicated feelings.

About the role familial connections played in the success of many alumni. About whether the practice of legacy admissions, which has long favored white families, should be eliminated just as a more diverse generation of graduates is getting ready to send its own children to college. About how to reconcile the belief that privileges for the privileged are wrong with the parental impulse to do whatever they can for their own children.

With the end of race-based affirmative action, the practice of giving admissions preference to relatives of alumni is particularly under fire at the most elite institutions, given the outsized presence of their alumni in the nation’s highest echelons of power. A new analysis of data from elite colleges published last week underscored how legacy admissions have effectively served as affirmative action for the privileged. Children of alumni, who are more likely to come from rich families, were nearly four times as likely to be admitted as other applicants with the same test scores.",0.2065493646138807,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/30/multimedia/30nat-legacies-03-bjpw/30nat-legacies-03-bjpw-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['ms. james-chakraborty', 'universities —', 'ultra-elite ones —', 'legacy admissions', 'broader implications', 'supreme court', 'admissions programs', 'role familial connections', 'legacy admissions', 'white families', 'diverse generation', 'own children', 'parental impulse', 'own children', 'affirmative action', 'admissions preference', 'elite institutions', 'nation ’ s', 'new analysis', 'elite colleges', 'legacy admissions', 'affirmative action', 'rich families', 'test scores']","[('James-Chakraborty', 'PERSON'), ('the Supreme Court', 'ORG'), ('last month', 'DATE'), ('last week', 'DATE'), ('nearly four', 'CARDINAL')]",Politics
A Left-Right Alliance Puts Iowa’s CO2 Pipelines on the Presidential Agenda,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/30/us/politics/iowa-pipelines-trump.html,"The $4.5 billion Summit, $3 billion Navigator and $630 million Wolf Carbon pipelines may not be front and center next month at the first Republican presidential debate. They probably won’t be featured in super PAC advertising or mentioned during Fox News appearances. But the pipelines capture a national debate with local consequences, and they will give candidates a chance to showcase their understanding of Iowa, the first state to weigh in on the Republican nominating fight — if they can navigate the issue.

The Summit, Navigator and Wolf pipelines, fueled by federal tax credits embraced by both parties, would draw carbon dioxide from the factories that turn Iowa corn into ethanol. They would snake through 3,300 miles of farmland in Iowa and other Midwestern states, then pump the planet-warming gas into the bedrock beneath Illinois and North Dakota. And they are pitched as a climate protection measure, though some experts and environmentalists say it is only a partial solution at best.

Earlier this month, an Iowa woman seemed to stump the front-runner, former President Donald J. Trump, when she asked how he would “help us in Iowa save our farmland from the CO2 pipelines.”

Mr. Trump stammered that he was “working on that” and that he “had a plan to totally, uh, it’s such a ridiculous situation,” before reassuring the crowd, “if we win, that’s going to be taken care of.”",0.13166666666666668,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/26/us/politics/26pol-pipeline-new1/26pol-pipeline-new1-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['summit', 'navigator', 'wolf carbon', 'republican', 'presidential debate', '’ t', 'pac', 'fox', 'news appearances', 'national debate', 'local consequences', 'iowa', 'republican', 'fight —', 'summit', 'navigator', 'wolf', 'federal tax credits', 'carbon dioxide', 'iowa', 'iowa', 'midwestern', 'illinois', 'dakota', 'climate protection measure', 'partial solution', 'iowa', 'donald j. trump', 'iowa', 'co2', 'pipelines. ”', 'mr. trump', '’ s', 'ridiculous situation', '’ s']","[('$4.5 billion', 'MONEY'), ('$3 billion', 'MONEY'), ('$630 million', 'MONEY'), ('Wolf Carbon', 'PERSON'), ('next month', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Fox News', 'ORG'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Navigator', 'ORG'), ('Wolf', 'PERSON'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('3,300 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('Midwestern', 'NORP'), ('Illinois', 'GPE'), ('North Dakota', 'GPE'), ('Earlier this month', 'DATE'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('Donald J. Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON')]",Politics
Nuts-and-Bolts Conservatism From Nikki Haley,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/30/us/politics/nikki-haley-stump-speech.html,"“Instead of 87,000 I.R.S. agents, we’ll put 25,000 Border Patrol and ICE agents on the ground, and we will let them do their job.”

The promise — and its reception — underscore the fixation of the Republican base with the nation’s Southwestern border. She also echoes misleading claims from Republican lawmakers that Democrats are seeking to hire an army of tax auditors under the Internal Revenue Service to scrutinize the financial filings of middle-class families. Like many of the other Republican candidates, Ms. Haley sides with Mr. Trump on border and immigration policy, pledging to build a wall, defund sanctuary cities and bring back a Trump-era program requiring asylum seekers to wait out their cases in Mexico. “Because guess what? Nobody wants to remain in Mexico,” she adds, sometimes garnering laughs.

“We will make sure that every member of Congress has to get their health care through the V.A. You watch how fast it gets fixed.”

Perhaps no other line in Ms. Haley’s stump speech draws a more passionate response from audiences than this one. She has pledged to tackle veteran homelessness and high suicide rates and to improve veterans’ access to health care. The issues are personal for Ms. Haley, whose husband, Michael, is a major in the South Carolina Army National Guard and served in Afghanistan in 2013. This summer, Ms. Haley joined other military spouses in seeing their partners off, as they deployed to Africa with the Army National Guard. The military tour is expected to last a year and for most of the G.O.P. primary race.

“Don’t you think it’s time we have term limits in Congress? We have to do it. We have to have term limits in Congress, and I think we need to have mental health competency tests for anyone over the age of 75.”

Ms. Haley, who has couched her campaign message in a call for “a new generation of leaders,” long sought to distinguish herself from competitors by taking an early stance on the issue of age limits among political leaders. Her shots are most directly aimed at President Biden, 80, whose age is cited as a top concern, as he seeks re-election. In an interview with Fox News, she suggested that Mr. Biden, would not live until the end of his second term if re-elected. On the stump, she often suggests that a vote for Mr. Biden is a vote for Vice President Kamala Harris.

“No more gender pronoun classes in the military. It is demoralizing to make them do that.”

Ms. Haley has faced blowback from Democrats, women’s rights groups and transgender rights activists for proposing that transgender girls playing in school sports is the “women’s issue of our time,” and for appearing to suggest that allowing “biological boys” in girls’ locker rooms was connected with the high rate of teenage girls who have considered suicide. She has since modified her statements so as not to link the two separate issues, but she has not dropped her focus on gender issues and implications that women are being erased. “Johns Hopkins recently came out and defined what a woman was,” she said in Hollis, referring to the research university. “Did you see it? A ‘nonman.’”",0.06956876456876457,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/30/multimedia/30pol-haley-fbvj/30pol-haley-fbvj-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['i.r.s', '’ ll', 'border patrol', 'ice', 'job. ”', 'reception — underscore', 'republican', 'nation ’ s', 'southwestern border', 'republican', 'tax auditors', 'internal', 'revenue service', 'financial filings', 'middle-class families', 'republican', 'ms. haley', 'mr. trump', 'immigration policy', 'defund sanctuary cities', 'trump-era', 'asylum seekers', 'mexico', 'mexico', 'congress', 'health care', 'v.a', 'fixed. ”', 'ms. haley', '’ s stump speech draws', 'passionate response', 'veteran homelessness', 'high suicide rates', 'veterans ’ access', 'health care', 'ms. haley', 'michael', 'carolina', 'national guard', 'afghanistan', 'ms. haley', 'military spouses', 'africa', 'national guard', 'military tour', 'g.o.p', 'primary race', 'don', '’ t', '’ s time', 'term limits', 'congress', 'term limits', 'congress', 'mental health competency tests', '75. ”', 'ms. haley', 'campaign message', 'new generation', 'early stance', 'age limits', 'political leaders', 'biden', 'top concern', 'fox', 'mr. biden', 'mr. biden', 'vice president', 'kamala harris', 'gender pronoun classes', 'that. ”', 'ms. haley', 'women ’ s rights groups', 'transgender rights activists', 'transgender girls', 'school sports', '“ women ’ s issue', '“ biological boys ”', 'girls ’ locker rooms', 'high rate', 'teenage girls', 'separate issues', 'gender issues', 'hopkins', 'hollis', 'research university', '‘ nonman', '’ ”']","[('87,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('I.R.S.', 'GPE'), ('25,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Southwestern', 'NORP'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Democrats', 'NORP'), ('the Internal Revenue Service', 'ORG'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Haley', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'ORG'), ('Mexico', 'GPE'), ('Mexico', 'GPE'), ('Congress', 'ORG'), ('Haley', 'PERSON'), ('Haley', 'PERSON'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('the South Carolina Army National Guard', 'ORG'), ('Afghanistan', 'GPE'), ('2013', 'DATE'), ('This summer', 'DATE'), ('Haley', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('the Army National Guard', 'ORG'), ('last a year', 'DATE'), ('G.O.P.', 'ORG'), ('Congress', 'ORG'), ('Congress', 'ORG'), ('the age of 75', 'DATE'), ('Haley', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'DATE'), ('Fox News', 'ORG'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Kamala Harris', 'PERSON'), ('Haley', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Johns Hopkins', 'ORG'), ('Hollis', 'GPE')]",Politics
Trump Team Creates Legal-Defense Fund to Cover His Allies’ Bills,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/30/us/politics/trump-legal-defense-fund.html,"Former President Donald J. Trump’s team is creating a legal-defense fund to handle some of the crush of legal bills stemming from the investigations and criminal indictments involving him and a number of employees and associates, according to two people with knowledge of the matter.

The fund, which is expected to be called the Patriot Legal Defense Fund Inc., will be led by Michael Glassner, a longtime Trump political adviser, according to the people familiar with the planning, who were not authorized to discuss it publicly. Another Trump aide who worked at the Trump Organization and then in Mr. Trump’s administration, Lynne Patton, will also be involved, the people said.

It is unclear how broad a group of people the legal-defense fund will cover, but one person said it was not expected to cover Mr. Trump’s own legal bills. In recent months Mr. Trump’s political action committee has paid legal bills for him and several witnesses, spending over $40 million on lawyers in the first half of 2023.

But a wide swath of people have become entangled in the various Trump-related criminal investigations, both as witnesses — of which there are many who work for Mr. Trump personally or did in the White House — as well as defendants.",0.06283333333333334,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/30/multimedia/30pol-legalfund-tcfj/30pol-legalfund-tcfj-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['donald j. trump', '’ s team', 'legal-defense fund', 'legal bills', 'criminal indictments', 'patriot legal', 'defense fund', 'michael glassner', 'trump', 'political adviser', 'trump', 'trump', 'mr. trump', '’ s administration', 'lynne patton', 'legal-defense fund', 'mr. trump', '’ s', 'own legal bills', 'recent months', 'mr. trump', '’ s', 'political action committee', 'legal bills', 'wide swath', 'trump-related', 'criminal investigations', 'witnesses —', 'mr. trump', 'white house —']","[('Donald J. Trump’s', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Patriot Legal Defense Fund Inc.', 'ORG'), ('Michael Glassner', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'ORG'), ('the Trump Organization', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Lynne Patton', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('recent months', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('$40 million', 'MONEY'), ('the first half of 2023', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('the White House', 'FAC')]",Politics
Minor Characters Emerge to Play Key Roles in Trump Documents Case,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/30/us/politics/trump-documents-de-oliveira-nauta.html,"Much of the story involves what prosecutors have said was a plot to move boxes of documents in and out of a storage room at Mar-a-Lago to avoid returning them to the government. Prosecutors say there was also a subsequent attempt to disguise those movements by seeking to delete footage from security cameras positioned outside the storage room.

According to the indictment, Mr. Nauta was central to the first part of the scheme, moving boxes from the room at least five times at Mr. Trump’s direction. All of that took place during a critical moment in the government’s investigation: the weeks between the issuance of a subpoena last year demanding the return of all classified documents in Mr. Trump’s possession and a visit to Mar-a-Lago shortly after by prosecutors seeking to collect the materials.

Mr. Nauta’s path to Mr. Trump and Mar-a-Lago was also characterized by a degree of turbulence.

A member of the Navy, Mr. Nauta had worked as a valet for Mr. Trump in the White House. But toward the end of his military career, Navy officials removed him from what is known as the Presidential Support Detail after learning he had fraternized with colleagues and subordinates in the White House mess, according to people with knowledge of the matter.

As naval officials were deciding what to do — including the possibility of sending Mr. Nauta back out to sea on a ship — an aide to Mr. Trump, who was already out of office, reached out to Mr. Nauta, offering him a job at Mar-a-Lago as the former president’s personal aide, according to a person familiar with the matter.

Mr. Nauta leaped at the opportunity, the person said, taking the job in July 2021 after receiving an honorable discharge from the Navy. It remains unclear whether Mr. Trump knew of Mr. Nauta’s troubles in the Navy at the end of his career.",0.014705882352941176,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/30/multimedia/30dc-investigate-chmf/30dc-investigate-chmf-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['story involves', 'storage room', 'mar-a-lago', 'prosecutors', 'subsequent attempt', 'delete footage', 'security cameras', 'storage room', 'according', 'mr. nauta', 'mr. trump', '’ s direction', 'critical moment', 'government ’ s investigation', 'mr. trump', '’ s possession', 'mar-a-lago', 'mr. nauta', '’ s path', 'mr. trump', 'mar-a-lago', 'mr. nauta', 'mr. trump', 'white house', 'military career', 'navy officials', 'support detail', 'white house mess', 'naval officials', 'mr. nauta', 'ship —', 'mr. trump', 'mr. nauta', 'mar-a-lago', 'president ’ s', 'personal aide', 'mr. nauta', 'july', 'honorable discharge', 'mr. trump', 'mr. nauta', '’ s troubles']","[('Mar-a-Lago', 'FAC'), ('Nauta', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('at least five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('the weeks', 'DATE'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Mar-a-Lago', 'PERSON'), ('Nauta', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Mar-a-Lago', 'PERSON'), ('Navy', 'ORG'), ('Nauta', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('the White House', 'FAC'), ('Navy', 'ORG'), ('the Presidential Support Detail', 'ORG'), ('the White House', 'ORG'), ('Nauta', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Nauta', 'PERSON'), ('Mar-a-Lago', 'FAC'), ('Nauta', 'PERSON'), ('July 2021', 'DATE'), ('Navy', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Nauta', 'PERSON'), ('Navy', 'ORG')]",Politics
Judge Dismisses Trump’s $475 Million Defamation Suit Against CNN,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/30/business/media/trump-cnn-lawsuit.html,"A federal judge has dismissed a $475 million defamation lawsuit that former President Donald J. Trump filed against CNN, ruling that all of the CNN statements that Mr. Trump cited were opinion and, therefore, Mr. Trump could not sue for defamation.

The suit, which the former president filed in October in U.S. District Court in Fort Lauderdale, Fla., alleged a “campaign of dissuasion in the form of libel and slander” that, Mr. Trump asserted, had escalated “as CNN fears the plaintiff will run for president in 2024.” The lawsuit said that the network’s use of the phrase “the big lie” in reference to Mr. Trump’s efforts to overturn the results of the 2020 presidential election was tantamount to comparing him to Adolf Hitler and Nazism.

Judge Raag Singhal, who was nominated to the District Court by Mr. Trump in 2019, stated in dismissing the suit late Friday night that CNN’s use of the phrase in connection with Mr. Trump’s election challenges “does not give rise to a plausible inference that Trump advocates the persecution and genocide of Jews or any other group of people.”

The judge added: “The Court finds Nazi references in the political discourse (made by whichever ‘side’) to be odious and repugnant. But bad rhetoric is not defamation when it does not include false statements of fact.”",-0.1125,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/30/multimedia/30trump-lawsuit-1-hwlm/30trump-lawsuit-1-hwlm-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['federal judge', 'defamation lawsuit', 'donald j. trump', 'cnn', 'cnn', 'mr. trump', 'mr. trump', 'october', 'u.s.', 'district court', 'lauderdale', 'fla.', '“ campaign', 'slander ”', 'mr. trump', 'cnn', '2024. ”', 'network ’ s', 'phrase “', 'big lie ”', 'mr. trump', '’ s efforts', 'presidential election', 'adolf hitler', 'nazism', 'raag singhal', 'district court', 'mr. trump', 'cnn', '’ s', 'mr. trump', '’ s election', 'plausible inference', 'trump', 'jews', 'people. ”', 'nazi', 'political discourse', '‘ side ’', 'bad rhetoric', 'false statements']","[('$475 million', 'MONEY'), ('Donald J. Trump', 'PERSON'), ('CNN', 'ORG'), ('CNN', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('October', 'DATE'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('District Court', 'ORG'), ('Fort Lauderdale', 'GPE'), ('Fla.', 'GPE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('CNN', 'ORG'), ('2024', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('Adolf Hitler', 'PERSON'), ('Nazism', 'NORP'), ('Raag Singhal', 'PERSON'), ('the District Court', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('2019', 'DATE'), ('late Friday', 'DATE'), ('night', 'TIME'), ('CNN', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'ORG'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Nazi', 'NORP')]",Politics
Inside the Party Switch that Blew Up North Carolina Politics,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/30/us/inside-the-party-switch-that-blew-up-north-carolina-politics.html,"When Tricia Cotham, a former Democratic lawmaker, was considering another run for the North Carolina House of Representatives, she turned to a powerful party leader for advice. Then, when she jumped into the Democratic primary, she was encouraged by still other formidable allies.

She won the primary in a redrawn district near Charlotte, and then triumphed in the November general election by 18 percentage points, a victory that helped Democrats lock in enough seats to prevent, by a single vote, a Republican supermajority in the state House.

Except what was unusual — and not publicly known at the time — was that the influential people who had privately encouraged Ms. Cotham to run were Republicans, not Democrats. One was Tim Moore, the redoubtable Republican speaker of the state House. Another was John Bell, the Republican majority leader.

“I encouraged her to run because she was a really good member when she served before,” Mr. Bell recalled in an interview.",0.1823979591836735,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/27/multimedia/00nat-cotham-01-fjmq/00nat-cotham-01-fjmq-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['tricia cotham', 'democratic lawmaker', 'carolina', 'powerful party leader', 'democratic primary', 'formidable allies', 'redrawn district', 'charlotte', 'november', 'general election', 'percentage points', 'republican', 'state house', 'unusual —', 'time —', 'influential people', 'ms. cotham', 'tim moore', 'republican', 'state house', 'john bell', 'republican', 'majority leader', 'good member', 'mr. bell']","[('Tricia Cotham', 'PERSON'), ('Democratic', 'NORP'), ('North Carolina', 'GPE'), ('House of Representatives', 'ORG'), ('Democratic', 'NORP'), ('Charlotte', 'GPE'), ('November', 'DATE'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('Democrats', 'NORP'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('House', 'ORG'), ('Cotham', 'PERSON'), ('Republicans', 'NORP'), ('Democrats', 'NORP'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tim Moore', 'PERSON'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('the state House', 'ORG'), ('John Bell', 'PERSON'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Bell', 'PERSON')]",Politics
Trump Threatens Republicans Who Don’t Help Him Exact Vengeance,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/us/politics/trump-pennsylvania-rally.html,"Former President Donald J. Trump lashed out at Republicans in Congress while campaigning in Pennsylvania on Saturday, threatening members of his party who do not share his appetite for pursuing corruption investigations against President Biden and his family — and for retribution.

In a litany of grievances about his deepening legal woes and the direction of the country, the twice-indicted former president cast G.O.P. holdouts as meek during a rally in Erie, Pa., criticizing their response to what he described as politically motivated prosecutions against him.

“The Republicans are very high class,” he said. “You’ve got to get a little bit lower class.”

And then Mr. Trump, the overwhelming front-runner for the 2024 Republican presidential nomination, put party members on notice.

“Any Republican that doesn’t act on Democratic fraud should be immediately primaried,” said Mr. Trump, to the roaring approval of several thousand supporters at the Erie Insurance Arena. Throughout the night he referenced the case against Hunter Biden and accused the president of complicity in his son’s troubles.",0.0900625,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/29pol-trump-pa-03-vzfk/29pol-trump-pa-03-vzfk-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['donald j. trump', 'congress', 'pennsylvania', 'corruption investigations', 'biden', 'family —', 'legal woes', 'president cast', 'g.o.p', 'erie', 'pa.', 'high class', '’ ve', 'class. ”', 'mr. trump', 'republican', 'presidential nomination', 'party members', 'republican', 'doesn ’ t act', 'democratic fraud', 'mr. trump', 'erie', 'arena', 'throughout', 'hunter biden', 'son ’ s troubles']","[('Donald J. Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Republicans', 'NORP'), ('Congress', 'ORG'), ('Pennsylvania', 'GPE'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('G.O.P.', 'ORG'), ('Erie', 'GPE'), ('Pa.', 'GPE'), ('Republicans', 'NORP'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('2024', 'DATE'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Democratic', 'NORP'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('several thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Erie Insurance Arena', 'ORG'), ('the night', 'TIME'), ('Hunter Biden', 'PERSON')]",Politics
Biden Presses Ahead With Effort to Broker Israeli-Saudi Rapprochement,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/us/politics/biden-israel-saudi-arabia-negotiations.html,"Saudi demands for normalization with Israel have been expansive. Among other things, Saudi officials want a NATO-level alliance with the United States in which an attack on one is an attack on all, long a taboo among American policymakers who do not want to be committed to coming to the defense of a nondemocratic monarchy in case of war. And they want a civilian nuclear program despite longstanding opposition by Israel and the United States, which fear a nuclear arms race in the region.

Israeli officials who recently met with American counterparts were given the impression that while the first phase of the negotiations did not include any demand for significant Israeli concessions in their conflict with the Palestinians, it is now believed that a deal would require significant progress on the issue.

Israeli officials were told that King Salman, who has ceded much control to his son, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, intervened in the negotiations to insist any deal include a clear Israeli move toward the Palestinians, according to an Israeli defense official who spoke on the condition of anonymity to discuss sensitive information.

The Saudis, according to the Israeli impression, would not be satisfied with a promise by Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu not to annex the West Bank, something that is not even envisioned by the current government. Instead, they would demand significant action on the ground.

It is highly doubtful whether significant concessions to the Palestinians would be approved by the current right-wing Israeli coalition, and an internal push for such a proposal could dissolve the government. Opposition leaders have vehemently refused to join any government led by Mr. Netanyahu, but questions have come up in discussions with Americans about whether the leaders might relent if it meant establishing diplomatic relations with the Saudis.",0.08875000000000001,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/29dc-prexy-01-glzc/29dc-prexy-01-glzc-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['saudi', 'israel', 'saudi', 'nato-level', 'american policymakers', 'nondemocratic monarchy', 'nuclear program', 'longstanding opposition', 'israel', 'nuclear arms race', 'israeli', 'american counterparts', 'israeli', 'palestinians', 'significant progress', 'israeli', 'salman', 'crown', 'mohammed', 'salman', 'israeli', 'palestinians', 'israeli', 'sensitive information', 'saudis', 'israeli', 'prime', 'benjamin netanyahu', 'current government', 'significant action', 'significant concessions', 'palestinians', 'israeli', 'mr. netanyahu', 'diplomatic relations', 'saudis']","[('Saudi', 'NORP'), ('Israel', 'GPE'), ('Saudi', 'NORP'), ('NATO', 'ORG'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('Israel', 'GPE'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('Israeli', 'NORP'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Israeli', 'NORP'), ('Palestinians', 'NORP'), ('Israeli', 'NORP'), ('King Salman', 'PERSON'), ('Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman', 'PERSON'), ('Israeli', 'NORP'), ('Palestinians', 'NORP'), ('Israeli', 'NORP'), ('Saudis', 'NORP'), ('Israeli', 'NORP'), ('Benjamin Netanyahu', 'PERSON'), ('the West Bank', 'GPE'), ('Palestinians', 'NORP'), ('Israeli', 'NORP'), ('Netanyahu', 'PERSON'), ('Americans', 'NORP'), ('Saudis', 'NORP')]",Politics
"Trump and DeSantis Collide for First Time in Iowa, as Fortunes Diverge",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/us/politics/trump-desantis-republican-presidential-iowa-caucus.html,"When former President Donald J. Trump and Gov. Ron DeSantis of Florida shared the same stage at an Iowa Republican Party dinner on Friday, their appearances seemed to capture the basic dynamics of the 2024 presidential primary.

Mr. Trump played headliner. Mr. DeSantis was reduced to an opening act.

Even as Mr. Trump has been hit with two criminal indictments, with more possibly coming, he has only consolidated support in recent months, flashing the same resilience in Iowa that he has nationally.

Mr. Trump’s rivals have long circled Iowa as the early state where Mr. Trump, who finished a disappointing second in the 2016 Iowa caucuses, might be most vulnerable in 2024. But although some influential leaders have signaled their eagerness for an alternative, Mr. Trump arrived on Friday for one of his episodic visits as the undisputed front-runner, as Republicans look past his political and legal liabilities.",-0.005263157894736838,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/29pol-iowa-top-hgwk/29pol-iowa-top-hgwk-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['donald j. trump', 'gov', 'ron desantis', 'florida', 'iowa republican', 'party dinner', 'basic dynamics', 'presidential primary', 'mr. trump', 'mr. desantis', 'opening act', 'mr. trump', 'criminal indictments', 'recent months', 'iowa', 'mr. trump', '’ s rivals', 'iowa', 'early state', 'mr. trump', 'iowa', 'influential leaders', 'mr. trump', 'undisputed front-runner', 'legal liabilities']","[('Donald J. Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Ron DeSantis', 'PERSON'), ('Florida', 'GPE'), ('Iowa Republican Party', 'ORG'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('2024', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('DeSantis', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('recent months', 'DATE'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('2024', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Republicans', 'NORP')]",Politics
Rep. Dean Phillips Says He Is Considering a Run Against Biden,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/us/politics/dean-phillips-biden-2024.html,"Representative Dean Phillips, a Minnesota Democrat who has for months been saying in public what many in his party only whisper in private — that the 80-year-old President Biden should not seek re-election because of his age — said he was considering challenging Mr. Biden in next year’s primary.

Mr. Phillips, 54, is in his third term in Congress representing a district that includes the suburbs west of Minneapolis. In a text message, he confirmed his interest in running but declined a request to be interviewed. He said he had “been overwhelmed with outreach and encouragement” and needed to assess his next steps.

Mr. Phillips would be an extreme long shot if he were to challenge Mr. Biden. Polls show that Democrats, who were once wary about Mr. Biden seeking re-election, have coalesced behind him. The party’s major donor class is backing the president, who raised $72 million with the Democratic National Committee and his joint fund-raising committee during the three-month reporting period that ended June 30.

Mr. Phillips had $277,000 in his congressional fund-raising account at the end of June.

An heir to a Minnesota liquor fortune who showcased himself driving a gelato truck in his first House campaign, Mr. Phillips has been known in Congress for embracing the moderate suburban politics that were at the core of the general election coalition that propelled Mr. Biden’s 2020 victory. He was first elected in 2018, when he and dozens of fellow Democrats flipped Republican-held districts as suburban voters turned against President Donald J. Trump.",0.06369047619047617,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/29pol-phillips-vqtb/29pol-phillips-vqtb-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['dean phillips', 'minnesota democrat', 'private —', '80-year-old president', 'biden', 'age —', 'mr. biden', 'year ’ s primary', 'mr. phillips', 'congress', 'minneapolis', 'text message', 'encouragement ”', 'mr. phillips', 'long shot', 'mr. biden', 'mr. biden', 'party ’ s', 'major donor class', 'democratic national committee', 'joint fund-raising committee', 'june', 'mr. phillips', 'congressional fund-raising account', 'june', 'minnesota', 'liquor fortune', 'gelato truck', 'house campaign', 'mr. phillips', 'congress', 'moderate suburban politics', 'general election coalition', 'mr. biden', '’ s', 'republican-held', 'suburban voters', 'donald j. trump']","[('Dean Phillips', 'PERSON'), ('Minnesota', 'GPE'), ('Democrat', 'NORP'), ('months', 'DATE'), ('80-year-old', 'DATE'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('next year', 'DATE'), ('Phillips', 'PERSON'), ('54', 'DATE'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Congress', 'ORG'), ('Minneapolis', 'GPE'), ('Phillips', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'NORP'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('$72 million', 'MONEY'), ('the Democratic National Committee', 'ORG'), ('three-month', 'DATE'), ('June 30', 'DATE'), ('Phillips', 'PERSON'), ('277,000', 'MONEY'), ('the end of June', 'DATE'), ('Minnesota', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('House', 'ORG'), ('Phillips', 'PERSON'), ('Congress', 'ORG'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('2018', 'DATE'), ('dozens', 'CARDINAL'), ('Democrats', 'NORP'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Donald J. Trump', 'PERSON')]",Politics
U.S. Hunts Chinese Malware That Could Disrupt American Military Operations,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/us/politics/china-malware-us-military-bases-taiwan.html,"The Biden administration is hunting for malicious computer code it believes China has hidden deep inside the networks controlling power grids, communications systems and water supplies that feed military bases in the United States and around the world, according to American military, intelligence and national security officials.

The discovery of the malware has raised fears that Chinese hackers, probably working for the People’s Liberation Army, have inserted code designed to disrupt U.S. military operations in the event of a conflict, including if Beijing moves against Taiwan in coming years.

The malware, one congressional official said, was essentially “a ticking time bomb” that could give China the power to interrupt or slow American military deployments or resupply operations by cutting off power, water and communications to U.S. military bases. But its impact could be far broader, because that same infrastructure often supplies the houses and businesses of ordinary Americans, according to U.S. officials.

The first public hints of the malware campaign began to emerge in late May, when Microsoft said it had detected mysterious computer code in telecommunications systems in Guam, the Pacific island with a vast American air base, and elsewhere in the United States. But that turned out to be only the narrow slice of the problem that Microsoft could see through its networks.",-0.11066666666666668,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/28/multimedia/00dc-intel-01-jclp/00dc-intel-01-jclp-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['biden', 'malicious computer code', 'china', 'power grids', 'communications systems', 'water supplies', 'military bases', 'national security officials', 'chinese hackers', 'people ’ s', 'liberation', 'u.s.', 'military operations', 'beijing', 'taiwan', 'time bomb ”', 'china', 'slow american military deployments', 'u.s.', 'military bases', 'u.s.', 'public hints', 'malware campaign', 'may', 'microsoft', 'mysterious computer code', 'telecommunications systems', 'guam', 'pacific island', 'vast american air base', 'narrow slice', 'microsoft']","[('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('the People’s Liberation Army', 'ORG'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('Beijing', 'GPE'), ('Taiwan', 'GPE'), ('coming years', 'DATE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('Americans', 'NORP'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('late May', 'DATE'), ('Microsoft', 'ORG'), ('Guam', 'GPE'), ('Pacific', 'LOC'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('Microsoft', 'ORG')]",Politics
"The Dave Matthews Band, Reconsidered",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/briefing/the-dave-matthews-band-reconsidered.html,"The Dave Matthews Band is on tour, as they have been every summer, except 2020, for the past 30-odd years. Like the Grateful Dead and Phish, so-called jam bands with which it’s often lumped together, Dave Matthews has a deliriously passionate fan base that follows the band from city to city, reuniting with fellow disciples at preshow tailgates, showing off devotional tattoos, trading live recordings.

In the early ’90s, when I arrived for my first year at the University of Virginia, Dave Matthews was a local celebrity. His band played for five bucks every Tuesday night at the little bar down the street from campus. I’m a little embarrassed to admit it, but I never went to see them.

It would be years before the stereotype of Dave Matthews fans as “pot-smoking, tie-dye-touting former frat bros fawning over craft beers in parking lots between cornhole games,” as Perri Ormont Blumberg puts it, would become a widely understood social designation. But for those of us figuring out how to reconcile the rise of grunge with our carefully curated Manic Panic-dyed identities, a college bar band with a fiddle player was way too mainstream.

“You’re sort of defined as much by what you dislike as by what you like at that age,” Ben Sisario, a music reporter at The Times and one of my first college friends, said recently. Ben and I met on our first night at Virginia. He was wearing a T-shirt from the 1992 tour of the alt-rock band the Pixies; our friendship was cemented in the uncomplicated way of teenagers for whom there’s little distinction between who you listen to and who you are. We spent the next four years not going to Dave Matthews Band shows together.",-0.049925390266299365,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/29-THE-MORNING-NL/29-THE-MORNING-NL-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['dave matthews', 'past 30-odd years', 'grateful dead', 'phish', 'so-called jam bands', '’ s', 'dave matthews', 'passionate fan base', 'fellow disciples', 'preshow tailgates', 'devotional tattoos', 'early ’ 90s', 'virginia', 'dave matthews', 'local celebrity', '’ m', 'dave matthews', 'frat bros', 'craft beers', 'cornhole games', 'perri ormont blumberg', 'social designation', 'manic panic-dyed', 'fiddle player', '’ re sort', 'ben sisario', 'music reporter', 'college friends', 'ben', 'virginia', 't-shirt', 'alt-rock band', 'pixies', '’ s', 'dave matthews', 'band shows']","[('every summer', 'DATE'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('the past 30-odd years', 'DATE'), ('the Grateful Dead', 'FAC'), ('Phish', 'NORP'), ('Dave Matthews', 'PERSON'), ('the early ’90s', 'DATE'), ('my first year', 'DATE'), ('the University of Virginia', 'ORG'), ('Dave Matthews', 'PERSON'), ('five bucks', 'MONEY'), ('every Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('night', 'TIME'), ('years', 'DATE'), ('Dave Matthews', 'PERSON'), ('Perri Ormont', 'PERSON'), ('Ben Sisario', 'PERSON'), ('Times', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ben', 'PERSON'), ('our first night', 'TIME'), ('Virginia', 'GPE'), ('1992', 'DATE'), ('Pixies', 'PRODUCT'), ('the next four years', 'DATE'), ('Dave Matthews', 'PERSON')]",Politics
"Reluctant to Retire, Leaders Raise a Tough Question: How Old Is Too Old?",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/us/politics/mcconnell-feinstein-biden-age.html,"After a series of troubling moments this week, an uncomfortable question has become unavoidable, leaving voters, strategists and even politicians themselves wondering: Just how old is too old to serve in public office?

For years, like so many children of aging parents across America, politicians and their advisers in Washington tried to skirt that difficult conversation, wrapping concerns about their octogenarian leaders in a cone of silence. The omertà was enabled by the traditions of a city that arms public figures with a battalion of aides, who manage nearly all of their professional and personal lives.

“I don’t know what the magic number is, but I do think that as a general rule, my goodness, when you get into the 80s, it’s time to think about a little relaxation,” said Trent Lott, 81, a former Senate majority leader who retired at the spry age of 67 to start his own lobbying firm. “The problem is, you get elected to a six-year term, you’re in pretty good shape, but four years later you may not be so good.”

Two closely scrutinized episodes this week thrust questions about aging with dignity in public office out of the halls of Congress and into the national conversation.",0.11011904761904762,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/29pol-age-memo-ltqw/29pol-age-memo-ltqw-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['uncomfortable question', 'public office', 'america', 'washington', 'difficult conversation', 'octogenarian leaders', 'public figures', 'personal lives', 'don ’ t', 'magic number', 'general rule', '’ s time', 'trent lott', 'senate majority leader', 'spry age', 'six-year term', '’ re', 'pretty good shape', 'good. ”', 'week thrust questions', 'public office', 'congress', 'national conversation']","[('this week', 'DATE'), ('years', 'DATE'), ('America', 'GPE'), ('Washington', 'GPE'), ('80s', 'DATE'), ('Trent Lott', 'PERSON'), ('81', 'DATE'), ('Senate', 'ORG'), ('67', 'CARDINAL'), ('six-year', 'DATE'), ('four years later', 'DATE'), ('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('this week', 'DATE'), ('Congress', 'ORG')]",Politics
"Trump, Spared Attacks by Rivals in Iowa, Doesn’t Return the Favor",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/28/us/politics/lincoln-dinner-iowa-2024.html,"They proved as good as their word when the evening’s second speaker, former Gov. Asa Hutchinson of Arkansas, breached the 10-minute mark and had to deliver the final words of his speech to a dead microphone with the country song “Only in America” playing loudly over him.

Before he was cut off, Mr. Hutchinson, who is polling at around 1 percent, also took a shot at the front-runner, saying, “You will be voting in Iowa while multiple criminal cases are pending against former President Trump.”

As the race takes shape five months ahead of the crucial Iowa caucuses, Mr. Trump is surging ahead of a fractured field of rivals who are largely reluctant to criticize him, cowed by his fiercely loyal base.

But Mr. Trump’s legal troubles could still provide an opening for one of his rivals. The former president has now been indicted twice, and major new charges were added to one of those cases on Thursday. He also is expected to face two additional criminal cases. So far, however, the charges against him have seemed to coalesce Republican voters around his candidacy At the dinner, Mr. Hurd, a former C.I.A. officer, most pointedly mentioned the charges, and he also contradicted Mr. Trump’s false assertion that he had won the 2020 election.

“One of the things we need in our elected leaders is for them to tell the truth, even if it’s unpopular,” Mr. Hurd said. “Donald Trump is not running to make America great again. Donald Trump is not running for president to represent the people that voted for him in 2016 or 2020. Donald Trump is running to stay out of prison.”",0.03385930735930735,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/28/multimedia/28pol-lincoln-pence-blfc/28pol-lincoln-pence-blfc-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['evening ’ s', 'gov', 'asa hutchinson', 'arkansas', '10-minute mark', 'final words', 'dead microphone', 'country song “', 'america', 'mr. hutchinson', 'iowa', 'multiple criminal cases', 'trump.', 'iowa', 'mr. trump', 'loyal base', 'mr. trump', '’ s', 'legal troubles', 'major new charges', 'additional criminal cases', 'republican', 'mr. hurd', 'c.i.a', 'mr. trump', '’ s', 'false assertion', '’ s unpopular', 'mr. hurd', 'donald trump', 'america', 'donald trump', 'donald trump']","[('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Asa Hutchinson', 'PERSON'), ('Arkansas', 'GPE'), ('10-minute', 'TIME'), ('Only in America', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Hutchinson', 'PERSON'), ('around 1 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('five months', 'DATE'), ('Iowa', 'GPE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Hurd', 'PERSON'), ('C.I.A.', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hurd', 'PERSON'), ('Donald Trump', 'PERSON'), ('America', 'GPE'), ('Donald Trump', 'PERSON'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('Donald Trump', 'PERSON')]",Politics
"After $700 Million U.S. Bailout, Trucking Firm Is Shutting Down",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/28/business/bailout-trucking-firm-yellow-yrc-shutdown.html,"Yellow, the beleaguered trucking company that received a $700 million pandemic loan from the federal government, notified staff on Friday that it is shutting down and laying off employees at all of its locations.

The move comes ahead of an expected bankruptcy filing by Yellow in the coming days. The closure of the company would mean the loss of approximately 30,000 jobs and mark the end of a business that just three years ago was deemed so critical to the nation’s supply chains that it warranted a federal bailout.

“The company is shutting down its regular operations on July 28, 2023, closing and/or laying off employees at all of its locations, including yours,” the company said in a memo to staff that was reviewed by The New York Times.

Yellow has been locked in protracted labor negotiations with International Brotherhood of Teamsters over a new contract that the company has said is essential to its ability to move forward with a restructuring plan.",-0.06077741702741703,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/28/multimedia/28dcYellow-hmbg/28dcYellow-hmbg-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['yellow', 'pandemic loan', 'federal government', 'yellow', 'nation ’ s', 'federal bailout', 'regular operations', 'july', 'york', 'yellow', 'labor negotiations', 'brotherhood', 'teamsters', 'new contract']","[('$700 million', 'MONEY'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('Yellow', 'PERSON'), ('the coming days', 'DATE'), ('approximately 30,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('just three years ago', 'DATE'), ('July 28, 2023', 'DATE'), ('The New York Times', 'ORG'), ('Yellow', 'PERSON'), ('International Brotherhood of Teamsters', 'ORG')]",Politics
Biden Acknowledges Granddaughter in Arkansas for First Time,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/28/us/politics/biden-hunter-navy-joan-roberts-grandchild.html,"Hunter Biden, 53, who is recovering from crack cocaine addiction, is the last surviving son of the president, who lost his eldest, Beau, to brain cancer in 2015. The younger Mr. Biden, who has five children, has said that he fathered Navy at a low point in his life and that he did not have a relationship with her.

President Biden had followed his son’s lead, referring to six grandchildren instead of seven.

“I have six grandchildren. And I’m crazy about them,” the president told a group of children in April. “And I speak to them every single day. Not a joke.”

In White House strategy meetings, aides have been told that the Bidens have six, not seven, grandchildren, according to two people familiar with the discussions.

But in recent weeks, the president told his son that he wanted to meet Navy when the time was right, according to a person familiar with those discussions. The person was not authorized to speak publicly.

On Friday, another person familiar with the situation said the president would say that he had seven grandchildren going forward. The person spoke on the condition of anonymity to discuss a private matter.",0.056868131868131874,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/28/multimedia/28DC-biden-vqpk/28DC-biden-vqpk-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['hunter biden', 'crack cocaine addiction', 'beau', 'brain cancer', 'mr. biden', 'low point', 'biden', 'son ’ s lead', '’ m', 'april', 'joke. ”', 'white house strategy meetings', 'bidens', 'recent weeks', 'private matter']","[('Hunter Biden', 'PERSON'), ('53', 'DATE'), ('Beau', 'PERSON'), ('2015', 'DATE'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Navy', 'ORG'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('every single day', 'DATE'), ('White House', 'ORG'), ('Bidens', 'GPE'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('recent weeks', 'DATE'), ('Navy', 'ORG'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')]",Politics
New Trump Charges Highlight Long-Running Questions About Obstruction,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/28/us/politics/trump-charges-obstruction.html,"“Demanding that evidence be destroyed is the most basic form of obstruction and is easy for a jury to understand,” said Mr. Goldstein, who is now a white-collar defense lawyer at the firm Cooley.

“It is more straightforwardly criminal than the obstructive acts we detailed in the Mueller report,” he said. “And if proven, it makes it easier to show that Trump had criminal intent for the rest of the conduct described in the indictment.”

The accusation about Mr. Trump’s desire to have evidence destroyed adds another chapter to what observers of his career say is a long pattern of gamesmanship on his part with prosecutors, regulators and others who have the ability to impose penalties on his conduct.

And it demonstrates how Mr. Trump viewed the conclusion of the Mueller investigation as a vindication of his behavior, which became increasingly emboldened — particularly in regards to the Justice Department — throughout the rest of his presidency, a pattern that appears to have continued despite having lost the protections of the office when he was defeated in the election.

In his memoir of his years in the White House, John R. Bolton, who served as Mr. Trump’s third national security adviser, described Mr. Trump’s approach as “obstruction as a way of life.”",0.07916666666666666,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/28/multimedia/28dc-trump-obstruction-01-tqhj/28dc-trump-obstruction-01-tqhj-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['demanding', 'basic form', 'mr. goldstein', 'white-collar defense lawyer', 'cooley', 'obstructive acts', 'mueller', 'trump', 'criminal intent', 'indictment. ”', 'mr. trump', '’ s desire', 'long pattern', 'impose penalties', 'mr. trump', 'mueller', 'justice department —', 'white house', 'john r. bolton', 'mr. trump', '’ s', 'national security adviser', 'mr. trump', '’ s approach', '“ obstruction']","[('Goldstein', 'PERSON'), ('Cooley', 'GPE'), ('Mueller', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Mueller', 'ORG'), ('the Justice Department', 'ORG'), ('the White House', 'FAC'), ('John R. Bolton', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Trump', 'PERSON')]",Politics
"Hugh Carter Jr., Who Pinched Pennies for a President, Dies at 80",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/28/us/politics/hugh-carter-jr-dead.html,"Hugh Carter Jr., who helped run the presidential campaign of his cousin Jimmy Carter, then became an aide in charge of reining in the White House budget, earning the nickname “Cousin Cheap” among staff members, died on Sunday at his home in Tampa, Fla. He was 80.

A funeral notice in The Atlanta Journal-Constitution announced his death but did not give a cause.

President Carter’s grandson, Jason, said in a statement on the website of the Carter Center, the human rights organization founded by President Carter, that Hugh Carter “was crucial in my grandfather’s election as president by organizing the famous Peanut Brigade, and he skillfully implemented true zero-based budgeting within my grandfather’s White House.”

The Peanut Brigade was a group of Georgians who hit the campaign trail for Jimmy Carter, a former governor of Georgia (who had taken over his father’s peanut farm), helping to give him the national profile he lacked and the momentum that led to the Democratic nomination. Hugh Carter, known as Sonny, recruited a number of those volunteers and often handled the logistics of getting them to crucial primary states to do grass-roots campaigning.",0.1409090909090909,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/28HCARTER-hplz-print1/28HCARTER-hplz-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['hugh carter jr.', 'presidential campaign', 'jimmy carter', 'white house budget', 'nickname “', 'cousin cheap', 'staff members', 'tampa', 'fla', 'funeral notice', 'atlanta journal-constitution', 'carter', '’ s grandson', 'jason', 'carter', 'human rights organization', 'carter', 'hugh carter', 'grandfather ’ s election', 'peanut brigade', 'grandfather ’ s', 'house.', 'peanut brigade', 'georgians', 'campaign trail', 'jimmy carter', 'georgia', 'father ’ s peanut farm', 'national profile', 'democratic nomination', 'hugh carter', 'sonny', 'crucial primary states']","[('Hugh Carter Jr.', 'PERSON'), ('Jimmy Carter', 'PERSON'), ('White House', 'ORG'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Tampa', 'GPE'), ('Fla.', 'GPE'), ('80', 'DATE'), ('The Atlanta Journal-Constitution', 'ORG'), ('Carter', 'PERSON'), ('Jason', 'PERSON'), ('the Carter Center', 'ORG'), ('Carter', 'PERSON'), ('Hugh Carter', 'PERSON'), ('Peanut Brigade', 'ORG'), ('zero', 'CARDINAL'), ('White House', 'ORG'), ('The Peanut Brigade', 'ORG'), ('Georgians', 'PERSON'), ('Jimmy Carter', 'PERSON'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('Democratic', 'NORP'), ('Hugh Carter', 'PERSON'), ('Sonny', 'PERSON')]",Politics
A Theory of Childbirth’s Evolution May Not Be What You’re Expecting,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/30/science/childbirth-evolution-obstetrical-dilemma.html,"But a detailed review of the evidence, slated to be published soon in the journal Evolutionary Anthropology, threw cold water on the idea. In the review, Anna Warrener, a biological anthropologist at the University of Colorado Denver, argued that the evidence to date did not offer strong support for the obstetrical dilemma, and that scientists had not paid enough attention to possible alternatives. What’s more, the scientist said, the idea sends a pernicious message to women that pregnancy is inherently dangerous.

“It perpetuates a narrative of bodily incompetence,” Dr. Warrener said.

In graduate school, Dr. Warrener did not see any reason to doubt the obstetrical dilemma. For her dissertation, she investigated one of Dr. Washburn’s key assumptions — that women walk less efficiently than men do because their pelvis is wider for childbirth. But in 2015, after studying volunteers walking on treadmills, Dr. Warrener found that having a wider pelvis did not create a bigger demand for oxygen.

“The data came in, and I was like, Wait a minute — I may have gotten some of the story wrong,” she recalled.

Holly Dunsworth, a biological anthropologist now at the University of Rhode Island, also became disenchanted with the obstetrical dilemma when she took a close look at the evidence. “I was scandalized,” she said.

In 2012, she and her colleagues published a study on the length of pregnancies in humans and other primates. They found that, in general, bigger primates tended to have longer pregnancies than smaller ones. For their size, humans don’t have shortened pregnancies. If anything, human pregnancies are longer than one would predict for a primate of their size.",-0.03578431372549019,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/08/01/science/00SCI-ORIGINS-obstetrical-dilemma/00SCI-ORIGINS-obstetrical-dilemma-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['evolutionary anthropology', 'cold water', 'anna warrener', 'biological anthropologist', 'colorado denver', 'strong support', 'obstetrical dilemma', 'possible alternatives', '’ s', 'idea sends', 'pernicious message', 'bodily incompetence', '” dr.', 'warrener', 'graduate school', 'warrener', 'obstetrical dilemma', 'washburn', '’ s key assumptions —', 'warrener', 'wait', 'minute —', 'holly dunsworth', 'biological anthropologist', 'rhode', 'obstetrical dilemma', 'close look', 'humans don ’ t', 'human pregnancies']","[('Evolutionary Anthropology', 'ORG'), ('Anna Warrener', 'PERSON'), ('the University of Colorado Denver', 'ORG'), ('Warrener', 'PERSON'), ('Warrener', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Washburn', 'PERSON'), ('2015', 'DATE'), ('Warrener', 'PERSON'), ('Holly Dunsworth', 'PERSON'), ('the University of Rhode Island', 'ORG'), ('2012', 'DATE')]",Science
"Worms Revived After 46,000 Years Frozen in Siberian Permafrost",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/science/roundworm-nematodes-siberia-permafrost.html,"At a time when the mighty woolly mammoth roamed the Earth, some 46,000 years ago, a minuscule pair of roundworms became encased in the Siberian permafrost.

Millennia later, the worms, thawed out of the ice, would wriggle again, and demonstrate to scientists that life could be paused — almost indefinitely.

The discovery, published this week in the peer-reviewed journal PLOS Genetics, offers new insight into how the worms, also known as nematodes, can survive in extreme conditions for extraordinarily long periods of time, in this case tens of thousands of years.

In 2018, Anastasia Shatilovich, a scientist from the Institute of Physicochemical and Biological Problems in Soil Science RAS in Russia, thawed two female worms from a fossilized burrow dug by gophers in the Arctic.",0.0659090909090909,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/29xp-worm-01/29xp-worm-01-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['earth', 'minuscule pair', 'siberian', 'millennia', 'plos genetics', 'new insight', 'extreme conditions', 'long periods', 'case tens', 'anastasia shatilovich', 'physicochemical', 'biological problems', 'soil', 'ras', 'russia', 'female worms', 'arctic']","[('Earth', 'LOC'), ('some 46,000 years ago', 'DATE'), ('Siberian', 'NORP'), ('Millennia', 'GPE'), ('this week', 'DATE'), ('PLOS Genetics', 'ORG'), ('tens of thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('2018', 'DATE'), ('Anastasia Shatilovich', 'ORG'), ('the Institute of Physicochemical', 'ORG'), ('Soil Science', 'ORG'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arctic', 'LOC')]",Science
Titanium Clouds Engulf This Ultrahot Neptune-like Planet,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/27/science/space/titanium-clouds-exoplanet.html,"Astronomers have come across the shiniest planet ever found, a mere 265 light years from our solar system. But that’s hardly its only standout trait. Shrouded by thick metallic clouds, this world’s temperature reaches a blistering 3,000 degrees Fahrenheit, and it quite likely rains scorching-hot drops of titanium.

The find, named LTT 9779 b, was described in a paper published this month in the journal Astronomy & Astrophysics. Nearly five times as big as Earth, it’s one of the few ultrahot, gaseous exoplanets of this size that scientists have discovered.

“This opens a new window into understanding these kinds of extreme, Neptune-like planets — maybe some of the rarest planets that exist,” said James Jenkins, an astronomer at Diego Portales University in Chile, describing this one as probably having “a nasty, harsh, dark environment.”

Initially detected in 2018 by NASA’s Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite, scientists quickly realized that this planet was an oddball. Usually worlds with short orbital periods are either like hot Jupiters, more than 10 times the size of Earth, or are small rocky orbs whose atmospheres have been stripped away by stellar radiation. But LTT 9779 b, which sprints around its star once every 19 hours, is midsize — making it one of four or five planets in the so-called Neptune desert, and the only one with an intact atmosphere.",-0.05638998682476943,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/27/science/27sci-titanium-clouds/27sci-titanium-clouds-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['astronomers', 'shiniest planet', 'light years', 'solar system', '’ s', 'standout trait', 'shrouded', 'thick metallic clouds', 'world ’ s temperature', 'fahrenheit', 'likely rains scorching-hot drops', 'ltt', 'astronomy', 'astrophysics', 'earth', '’ s', 'gaseous exoplanets', 'new window', 'neptune-like', 'planets —', 'rarest planets', 'james jenkins', 'diego portales', 'chile', 'dark environment. ”', 'nasa', '’ s', 'transiting exoplanet survey satellite', 'short orbital periods', 'jupiters', 'earth', 'small rocky orbs', 'stellar radiation', 'ltt', 'midsize — making', 'neptune', 'intact atmosphere']","[('265 light years', 'DATE'), ('3,000 degrees', 'QUANTITY'), ('Fahrenheit', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('9779', 'CARDINAL'), ('this month', 'DATE'), ('Astronomy & Astrophysics', 'ORG'), ('Nearly five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Earth', 'LOC'), ('James Jenkins', 'PERSON'), ('Diego Portales University', 'ORG'), ('Chile', 'GPE'), ('2018', 'DATE'), ('NASA', 'ORG'), ('Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite', 'ORG'), ('more than 10', 'CARDINAL'), ('Earth', 'LOC'), ('9779', 'DATE'), ('every 19 hours', 'TIME'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('four or five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Neptune', 'LOC')]",Science
A Looming Retraction Casts a Shadow Over a Field of Physics,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/26/science/ranga-dias-retraction-physics.html,"A major physics journal is retracting a two-year-old scientific paper that described the transformations of a chemical compound as it was squeezed between two pieces of diamond.

Such an esoteric finding — and retraction — would not typically garner much attention.

But one of the leaders of this research is Ranga P. Dias, a professor in the physics and mechanical engineering departments at the University of Rochester in New York who made a much bigger scientific splash earlier this year, touting the discovery of a room-temperature superconductor.

At the same time, accusations of research misconduct have swirled around Dr. Dias, and his superconductor findings remain largely unconfirmed.

The retracted paper does not involve superconductivity but rather describes how a relatively mundane material, manganese sulfide, shifts its behavior from an insulator to a metal and then back to an insulator under increasing pressure.",0.0481650924832743,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/26/multimedia/26sci-retraction-01-mfgt/26sci-retraction-01-mfgt-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['major physics journal', 'scientific paper', 'chemical compound', 'retraction —', 'ranga p. dias', 'mechanical engineering departments', 'rochester', 'york', 'scientific splash', 'room-temperature superconductor', 'research misconduct', 'dias', 'superconductor findings', 'mundane material', 'manganese sulfide']","[('two-year-old', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ranga P. Dias', 'PERSON'), ('the University of Rochester', 'ORG'), ('New York', 'GPE'), ('earlier this year', 'DATE'), ('Dias', 'PERSON')]",Science
A Pancaked Turtle Fossil’s 150-Million-Year-Old Tale,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/26/science/turtle-pancake-fossil.html,"Today it is Bavaria, a region of Germany. But in the Late Jurassic Period, it was a shallow tropical archipelago ringed with sponge reefs. The hyper-saline, oxygen-poor conditions of these waters prevented scavengers from disturbing the bodies of animals that died in the lagoons.

Some 150 million years later, that has been very good news for paleontologists, who for more than 100 years have pulled complete fossils of everything from fish to marine reptiles, pterosaurs and feathered dinosaurs like Archaeopteryx from the Solnhofen Limestone.

The area’s latest find is a beautifully preserved — if pancaked — turtle. Described in an article published Wednesday in the journal PLOS One, the specimen represents an approach to marine life unlike that of any shelled reptile today.

The turtle’s name is Solnhofia, said Felix Augustin, a paleontologist at the University of Tübingen in Germany and an author of the study. Originally named in 1975, for decades the creature was known only from a pair of skulls found in Bavaria and Switzerland. A few more scrappy remains turned up in 2000.",0.18474358974358973,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/26/multimedia/26tb-turtle-pancake-02-fgkl/26tb-turtle-pancake-02-fgkl-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['bavaria', 'germany', 'late jurassic period', 'shallow tropical archipelago', 'sponge reefs', 'oxygen-poor conditions', 'good news', 'complete fossils', 'marine reptiles', 'archaeopteryx', 'solnhofen limestone', 'area ’ s', '— turtle', 'described', 'plos', 'marine life', 'turtle ’ s name', 'solnhofia', 'felix augustin', 'tübingen', 'germany', 'originally', 'bavaria', 'switzerland']","[('Today', 'DATE'), ('Bavaria', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Some 150 million years later', 'DATE'), ('more than 100 years', 'DATE'), ('Archaeopteryx', 'PRODUCT'), ('the Solnhofen Limestone', 'ORG'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('PLOS One', 'ORG'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Solnhofia', 'ORG'), ('Felix Augustin', 'PERSON'), ('the University of Tübingen', 'ORG'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('1975', 'DATE'), ('decades', 'DATE'), ('Bavaria', 'GPE'), ('Switzerland', 'GPE'), ('2000', 'DATE')]",Science
NASA Seeks a Nuclear-Powered Rocket to Get to Mars in Half the Time,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/26/science/nasa-nuclear-rocket-darpa.html,"A Number That Sums It Up: 3 to 4 months to Mars

What if a spacecraft could get to Mars in half the time it currently takes?

Every 26 months or so, Mars and Earth are close enough for a shorter journey between the worlds. But even then it is a pretty long trip, lasting seven to nine months. For most of the time, the spacecraft is just coasting through space.

But if the spacecraft could continue accelerating through the first half of the journey and then start slowing down again, the travel time could be slashed. Current rocket engines, which typically rely on the combustion of a fuel like hydrogen or methane with oxygen, are not efficient enough to accomplish that; there is not enough room in the spacecraft to carry that much propellant.

But nuclear reactions, generating energy from the splitting of uranium atoms, are much more efficient.

The DRACO engine would consist of a nuclear reactor that would heat hydrogen from a chilly minus 420 degrees Fahrenheit to a toasty 4,400 degrees, with the hot gas shooting from a nozzle to generate thrust. Greater fuel efficiency could speed up journeys to Mars, reducing the amount of time astronauts spend exposed to the treacherous environment of deep space.

Nuclear propulsion could also have uses closer to home, which is why DARPA is investing in the project. The technology may allow rapid maneuvers of military satellites in orbit around Earth.

Background: Back to the future

Nuclear propulsion for space is not a new idea. In the 1950s and 1960s, Project Orion — financed by NASA, the Air Force and the Advanced Research Projects Agency — contemplated using the explosions of atomic bombs to accelerate spacecraft.

At the same time, NASA and other agencies also undertook Project Rover and Project NERVA, efforts that aimed to develop nuclear-thermal engines similar in concept to those now being pursued by the DRACO program. A series of 23 reactors were built and tested, but none were ever launched to space. Until the end of this program in 1973, NASA had contemplated using nuclear reactors to propel space probes to Jupiter, Saturn and beyond, as well as to provide power at a lunar base.

“The technical capabilities, including early safety protocols, remain viable today,” Tabitha Dodson, the DRACO project manager, said in a news briefing on Wednesday.

A key difference between NERVA and DRACO is that NERVA used weapons-grade uranium for its reactors, while DRACO will use a less-enriched form of uranium.

The reactor would not be turned on until it reached space, part of the precautions to minimize the possibility of a radioactive accident on Earth.

“DRACO has already done all of our preliminary analyses across the entire spectrum of possibilities for accidents and found that we’re all the way down in the low probability and all the way down in the teeny tiny amount of release,” Dr. Dodson said.

What Happens Next: A test flight in orbit

The DRACO development is to culminate with a flight test of the nuclear-thermal engine. The launch is currently scheduled for late 2026 or early 2027.

The demonstration spacecraft would most likely orbit at an altitude between 435 and 1,240 miles, Dr. Dodson said. That is high enough to ensure that it stays in orbit for more than 300 years, or long enough for radioactive elements in the reactor fuel to decay to safe levels, she said.",0.04019904931669637,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/26/science/26nuclear-rocket/26nuclear-rocket-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['number', 'sums', 'up', 'mars', 'mars', 'mars', 'earth', 'shorter journey', 'travel time', 'current', 'rocket engines', 'nuclear reactions', 'uranium atoms', 'draco', 'nuclear reactor', 'heat hydrogen', 'fahrenheit', 'hot gas shooting', 'generate thrust', 'fuel efficiency', 'mars', 'time astronauts', 'treacherous environment', 'deep space', 'nuclear', 'darpa', 'rapid maneuvers', 'military satellites', 'earth', 'background', 'nuclear', 'new idea', 'project orion', 'nasa', 'air force', 'advanced', 'projects', 'agency —', 'atomic bombs', 'accelerate spacecraft', 'nasa', 'project rover', 'project nerva', 'nuclear-thermal engines', 'draco', 'nasa', 'nuclear reactors', 'propel space probes', 'jupiter', 'saturn', 'lunar base', 'technical capabilities', 'early safety protocols', 'tabitha dodson', 'draco', 'project manager', 'key difference', 'nerva', 'draco', 'nerva', 'weapons-grade uranium', 'draco', 'radioactive accident', 'earth', 'draco', 'preliminary analyses', 'entire spectrum', '’ re', 'low probability', 'tiny amount', '” dr.', 'dodson', 'happens', 'test flight', 'draco', 'flight test', 'nuclear-thermal engine', 'demonstration spacecraft', 'likely orbit', 'dodson', 'radioactive elements', 'reactor fuel', 'safe levels']","[('3 to 4 months', 'DATE'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('half', 'CARDINAL'), ('Every 26 months or so', 'DATE'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Earth', 'LOC'), ('seven to nine months', 'DATE'), ('the first half', 'DATE'), ('DRACO', 'ORG'), ('420 degrees', 'QUANTITY'), ('Fahrenheit', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('4,400 degrees', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('DARPA', 'ORG'), ('Earth', 'LOC'), ('the 1950s and 1960s', 'DATE'), ('Project Orion', 'ORG'), ('NASA', 'ORG'), ('the Air Force', 'ORG'), ('the Advanced Research Projects Agency', 'ORG'), ('NASA', 'ORG'), ('Project Rover', 'ORG'), ('Project NERVA', 'ORG'), ('DRACO', 'ORG'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('1973', 'DATE'), ('NASA', 'ORG'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Saturn', 'PERSON'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Tabitha Dodson', 'PERSON'), ('DRACO', 'ORG'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('NERVA', 'ORG'), ('DRACO', 'ORG'), ('NERVA', 'ORG'), ('DRACO', 'ORG'), ('Earth', 'LOC'), ('DRACO', 'ORG'), ('Dodson', 'PERSON'), ('DRACO', 'ORG'), ('late 2026', 'DATE'), ('early 2027', 'DATE'), ('1,240 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Dodson', 'PERSON'), ('more than 300 years', 'DATE')]",Science
When Ancient Eruptions Pumped Diamonds to Earth’s Surface,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/26/science/kimberlite-diamonds-volcano-eruptions.html,"While diamonds might look pretty perched atop a ring, the rocks they hail from venture to Earth’s surface in a journey that’s anything but glamorous. Millions of years ago, some of our planet’s strangest and most violent volcanic outbursts dredged from deep underground most of the diamonds mined today in the form of blue-tinged rocks called kimberlites.

Unlike the volcanoes that more commonly pop up near the thinner edges of continents, the eruptions that produced most kimberlites came through the thick, stable continental cores known as cratons. Kimberlite eruptions start near the cratonic roots, at least 75 miles underground, and race upward at tens of feet per second — a fiery fury driven by an abundance of carbon dioxide and water.

“It’s like rocket fuel,” said Thomas Gernon, a geologist at the University of Southampton in England who has long studied kimberlites. The turbulent flow punches a carrot-shaped pipe through the ground, ripping out chunks of deep subsurface rock, including some that are studded with diamonds.

But existing research still has a giant diamond-shaped hole: Why do kimberlites form?

A new study led by Dr. Gernon and published Wednesday in the journal Nature points to the ancient roots of these eruptions. He and his colleagues report that the breakup of ancient supercontinents like Pangaea and Rodinia caused deep disruptions in the flow of the mantle beneath Earth’s crust, setting off the blasts.",0.04646464646464646,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/26/science/26tb-diamond-eruptions-01/26tb-diamond-eruptions-01-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['earth', '’ s surface', '’ s', 'millions', 'planet ’ s strangest', 'violent volcanic outbursts', 'thinner edges', 'stable continental cores', 'kimberlite', 'cratonic roots', 'fiery fury', 'carbon dioxide', '’ s', 'rocket fuel', 'thomas gernon', 'southampton', 'england', 'turbulent flow punches', 'deep subsurface rock', 'kimberlites form', 'new study', 'gernon', 'nature', 'ancient roots', 'ancient supercontinents', 'pangaea', 'rodinia', 'deep disruptions', 'earth', '’ s crust']","[('Earth', 'LOC'), ('Millions of years ago', 'DATE'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('kimberlites', 'NORP'), ('kimberlites', 'NORP'), ('at least 75 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('tens of feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('Thomas Gernon', 'PERSON'), ('the University of Southampton', 'ORG'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Gernon', 'PERSON'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('Nature', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Pangaea', 'GPE'), ('Rodinia', 'GPE'), ('Earth', 'LOC')]",Science
Scientist’s Deep Dive for Alien Life Leaves His Peers Dubious,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/24/science/avi-loeb-extraterrestrial-life.html,"Dr. Loeb also began studying the fireball catalog from the Center for Near Earth Object Studies at NASA. That led to the object that had been detected in 2014. From its direction and speed at impact — 28 miles per second — Dr. Loeb and Mr. Siraj concluded that the fireball had been moving too fast for something gravitationally bound to our sun. That meant, like Oumuamua, it must also have been interstellar.

They wrote a paper about the discovery in 2019. It was initially rejected by The Astrophysical Journal, but the same journal then accepted it for publication last November, several months after the U.S. Space Command announced in a memo circulated on Twitter that measurements of the fireball’s velocity were accurate enough to infer interstellar origin.

That appeal to authority isn’t enough, said Peter Brown, a meteor physicist at Western University in Ontario. It’s unknown how precise the U.S. Defense Department data is, which affects how likely it is that the object came from beyond.

“We know from experience, running ground-based radar and optical networks, that you often find several percent of all the events you detect appear to be interstellar,” Dr. Brown said. To date, he continued, nearly all of those events could be chalked up to measurement error.",0.05882352941176472,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/25/science/00sci-interstellar-new/00sci-interstellar-new-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['loeb', 'fireball catalog', 'near earth object studies', 'nasa', 'impact —', '— dr.', 'loeb', 'mr. siraj', 'oumuamua', 'astrophysical', 'november', 'u.s.', 'space command', 'twitter', 'fireball ’ s velocity', 'infer interstellar origin', 'authority isn ’ t', 'peter brown', 'meteor physicist', 'western university', 'ontario', '’ s', 'u.s.', 'defense department data', 'optical networks', '” dr.', 'brown', 'measurement error']","[('Loeb', 'PERSON'), ('the Center for Near Earth Object Studies', 'ORG'), ('NASA', 'ORG'), ('2014', 'DATE'), ('28 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Loeb', 'PERSON'), ('Siraj', 'PERSON'), ('Oumuamua', 'PERSON'), ('2019', 'DATE'), ('The Astrophysical Journal', 'ORG'), ('last November', 'DATE'), ('several months', 'DATE'), ('the U.S. Space Command', 'ORG'), ('Twitter', 'PRODUCT'), ('Peter Brown', 'PERSON'), ('meteor', 'ORG'), ('Western University', 'ORG'), ('Ontario', 'GPE'), ('the U.S. Defense Department', 'ORG'), ('Brown', 'PERSON')]",Science
‘A Dangerous Combination’: Teenagers’ Accidents Expose E-Bike Risks,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/health/ebikes-safety-teens.html,"Three days later, another teenage boy was taken to the same hospital after the e-bike he was riding collided with a car, leaving him sprawled beneath a BMW, hurt but alive. According to the police, the teen had been seen driving recklessly and was found to be at fault. In the days following, the town of Encinitas, where both incidents occurred, declared a state of emergency for e-bike safety.

The e-bike industry is booming, but the summer of 2023 has brought sharp questions about how safe e-bikes are, especially for teenagers. Many e-bikes can exceed the 20-mile-per-hour speed limit that is legal for teenagers in most states; some can go 70 miles an hour. But even when ridden at legal speeds, there are risks, especially for young, inexperienced riders merging into complex traffic with fast-moving cars and sometimes distracted drivers.

“The speed they are going is too fast for sidewalks, but it’s too slow to be in traffic,” said Jeremy Collis, a sergeant at the North Coastal Station of the San Diego County Sheriff’s Office, which is investigating Brodee’s accident. The investigation is ongoing pending a medical examiner’s finding.

To some policymakers and law enforcement officials, the technology has far outpaced existing laws, regulations and safety guidelines. Police and industry officials charge that some companies appear to knowingly sell products that can easily evade speed limits and endanger young riders.",0.09166666666666667,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/29ebike-risk-promo-pfmz/29ebike-risk-promo-pfmz-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['teenage boy', 'bmw', 'according', 'encinitas', 'e-bike safety', 'e-bike industry', 'sharp questions', 'safe e-bikes', '20-mile-per-hour speed limit', 'legal speeds', 'complex traffic', '’ s', 'jeremy collis', 'coastal', 'san diego', 'county sheriff ’ s office', 'brodee', '’ s accident', 'medical examiner ’ s', 'law enforcement officials', 'safety guidelines', 'industry officials charge', 'evade speed limits', 'young riders']","[('Three days later', 'DATE'), ('BMW', 'ORG'), ('the days', 'DATE'), ('Encinitas', 'GPE'), ('the summer of 2023', 'DATE'), ('20-mile-per-hour', 'QUANTITY'), ('70 miles an hour', 'QUANTITY'), ('Jeremy Collis', 'PERSON'), ('the North Coastal Station of', 'ORG'), ('the San Diego County Sheriff’s Office', 'GPE'), ('Brodee', 'ORG')]",Science
"What Is an E-Bike, and How Safe Are They?",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/29/health/ebikes-safety-regulation.html,"Class 1: Maximum speed, 20 m.p.h.; the motor may provide power only while the rider is pedaling. (This is known as “pedal assist.”) Age restrictions: None in most states, although some states, such as Oregon, do not permit the use of any class of e-bike by riders younger than 16.

Class 2: Maximum speed, 20 m.p.h.; the motor may provide power independently of the pedals. Age restrictions: none in most states. (These e-bikes in particular attract criticism because, by relying solely on the motor, they can achieve immediate bursts of speed.)

Class 3: Maximum speed, 28 m.p.h. — but only if the pedals and the motor are used simultaneously. These vehicles are intended for commuters and other riders who are interested in traveling farther than a traditional bicycle would easily allow. Use not permitted by riders younger than 16, in many states.

Notably, the federal consumer agency does not recognize the three-class system.

What Are the State Rules?

According to PeopleForBikes, the trade group that helped craft the three-class system for manufacturers, 42 states have laws that are largely in line with the classification system. In most states, then, riders under 16 can use Class 1 and Class 2 e-bikes, while riders of Class 3 e-bikes must be 16 or older.

But enforcing those rules is tricky, according to local and state law enforcement officials. It can be hard to tell by looking if a teenage rider is too young for the e-bike being ridden. And glancing at an e-bike’s motor does not establish whether it can go faster than 20 m.p.h.",0.15519480519480522,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/26/multimedia/00ebike-explainer-01-lhmq/00ebike-explainer-01-lhmq-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['maximum', '“ pedal assist. ”', 'age', 'oregon', 'maximum', 'age', 'immediate bursts', 'maximum', 'traditional bicycle', 'notably', 'federal consumer agency', 'three-class system', 'according', 'peopleforbikes', 'trade group', 'three-class system', 'classification system', 'state law enforcement officials', 'teenage rider', 'e-bike ’ s motor']","[('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Oregon', 'GPE'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('28', 'CARDINAL'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('42', 'CARDINAL'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('Class 1', 'DATE'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('16 or', 'DATE')]",Science
‘Swift Quake’: Taylor Swift Fans Shake Ground During Seattle Concert,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/28/arts/music/taylor-swift-earthquake-seattle-.html,"“I shake it off, I shake it off,” Taylor Swift sang. And boy did her fans deliver.

A Taylor Swift concert in downtown Seattle last weekend shook the ground so hard, it registered signals on a nearby seismometer roughly equivalent to a magnitude 2.3 earthquake, seismologists said.

“It’s certainly the biggest concert we’ve had in a while,” said Mouse Reusch, a seismologist at the Pacific Northwest Seismic Network, which monitors earthquake activity in the Pacific Northwest. “We’re talking about 70,000 people and all the music and paraphernalia associated with the concert.”

The so-called “Swift Quake” recorded a maximum ground acceleration of roughly 0.011 meters per second squared, said Jackie Caplan-Auerbach, a seismologist at Western Washington University.

Seismologists use acceleration to measure ground vibrations, which are then converted to the more conventional Richter scale, the common measurement for earthquakes.",-0.02202380952380953,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/28/multimedia/28xp-swift-quake-03/28xp-swift-quake-03-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['taylor swift', 'taylor swift', 'seattle', 'weekend shook', 'nearby seismometer', '’ s', '’ ve', 'reusch', 'seismic network', 'monitors earthquake activity', '’ re', 'concert. ”', 'so-called “', 'swift quake', 'maximum ground acceleration', 'jackie caplan-auerbach', 'washington', 'seismologists', 'ground vibrations', 'richter', 'common measurement']","[('Taylor Swift', 'PERSON'), ('Taylor', 'PERSON'), ('Seattle', 'GPE'), ('last weekend', 'DATE'), ('2.3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mouse Reusch', 'PERSON'), ('the Pacific Northwest Seismic Network', 'ORG'), ('the Pacific Northwest', 'LOC'), ('about 70,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Swift Quake', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('roughly 0.011 meters', 'QUANTITY'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Jackie Caplan-Auerbach', 'PERSON'), ('Western Washington University', 'ORG'), ('Seismologists', 'NORP')]",Science
When Connecting With Birds Connects People,https://www.nytimes.com/article/when-connecting-with-birds-connects-people.html,"Whether or not you’re into birds, joining a birding group can change your life.

Last week, we looked at groups that birders can join to make the activity a community affair. Our challenge for beginners was to try bird-watching with at least one other person. We also asked if anyone had met friends — or even a spouse — through a birding activity. We didn’t expect so many answers in the affirmative.

“I’m not sure it was our very first date, as she claims,” Rick Wright from Bloomfield, N.J., said. “But it was very early on that I invited a woman to go to the swine effluent ponds with me to look for shorebirds. She said yes. We’ve been married 25 years.”

For Gordon Dayton in Connecticut, it was the reverse. He was not interested in birding when he met his wife of many years, but the activity was something that happened along the way. “Some of us come to birding through love of birds, some through love of bird-lovers,” Mr. Dayton said.

Not everyone is eager to make birding anything more than a solitary activity. “I’m not a joiner,” Margaret Poethig from Arlington, Va., said. But as a beginner, she knew that other birders could help improve her skills. “So I started by participating in a local citizen science project, joined a couple of local bird clubs, went on a few bird walks and volunteered at a couple of club events.” Now she sometimes meets people who post checklists on her local eBird hot spot.",0.1465,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/05/20/multimedia/12-events-birding-community-science-wvqt/12-events-birding-community-science-wvqt-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['whether', '’ re', 'community affair', 'friends —', 'spouse —', 'didn ’ t', '’ m', 'rick wright', 'bloomfield', 'n.j.', 'swine effluent ponds', '’ ve', 'years. ”', 'gordon dayton', 'connecticut', 'mr. dayton', 'solitary activity', '’ m', 'margaret poethig', 'arlington', 'va.', 'local citizen science project', 'local bird clubs', 'club events. ”', 'post checklists', 'local ebird', 'hot spot']","[('Last week', 'DATE'), ('at least one', 'CARDINAL'), ('our very first date', 'DATE'), ('Rick Wright', 'PERSON'), ('Bloomfield', 'GPE'), ('N.J.', 'GPE'), ('25 years', 'DATE'), ('Gordon Dayton', 'PERSON'), ('Connecticut', 'GPE'), ('Dayton', 'PERSON'), ('Margaret Poethig', 'PERSON'), ('Arlington', 'GPE'), ('Va.', 'GPE'), ('eBird', 'PRODUCT')]",Science
"Aided by A.I. Language Models, Google’s Robots Are Getting Smart",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/28/technology/google-robots-ai.html,"A one-armed robot stood in front of a table. On the table sat three plastic figurines: a lion, a whale and a dinosaur.

An engineer gave the robot an instruction: “Pick up the extinct animal.”

The robot whirred for a moment, then its arm extended and its claw opened and descended. It grabbed the dinosaur.

Until very recently, this demonstration, which I witnessed during a podcast interview at Google’s robotics division in Mountain View, Calif., last week, would have been impossible. Robots weren’t able to reliably manipulate objects they had never seen before, and they certainly weren’t capable of making the logical leap from “extinct animal” to “plastic dinosaur.”",-0.0335978835978836,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/28/multimedia/28ROOSE-02-zwqm/28ROOSE-02-zwqm-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['plastic figurines', 'pick', 'extinct animal. ”', 'podcast interview', 'google', '’ s robotics division', 'mountain', 'calif.', 'robots', 'weren ’ t', 'weren ’ t', 'logical leap', '“ extinct animal ”', '“ plastic dinosaur']","[('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Google', 'ORG'), ('Mountain View', 'GPE'), ('Calif.', 'GPE'), ('last week', 'DATE')]",Science
"Louise Levy, Who Was Studied for Her Very Long Life, Is Dead at 112",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/27/health/louise-levy-dead.html,"When she celebrated her birthday last year, she told The Rye Record, “I’m glad I can still speak and have my sense of humor, but I would caution you not to try and live to be 112!”

She had been the oldest known living person in New York State, according to LongeviQuest, which maintains a database of supercentenarians, people who have lived into a 12th decade.

Mrs. Levy was one of more than 700 people, all 95 or older, recruited since 1998 to participate in a study by the Institute for Aging Research at the Albert Einstein School of Medicine in the Bronx to learn the genetic reasons for their unusually long, healthy lives.

“It’s not luck,” Dr. Nir Barzilai, an endocrinologist who directs the institute, said by phone. “They exceeded luck. The biggest answer is genetics.”

Using the blood and plasma of the test group, all Ashkenazi Jews — a comparatively homogeneous population whose genetic variations are easier to spot — the institute’s Longevity Genes Project has discovered gene mutations that are believed to be responsible for slowing the impact of aging on people like Mrs. Levy and protecting them against high cholesterol, heart disease, diabetes and Alzheimer’s disease.",0.2394077134986226,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/29/multimedia/23levy-kqpv-print1/23levy-kqpv-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg,2023,"['rye record', '’ m', 'york', 'longeviquest', 'mrs. levy', 'aging', 'albert einstein', 'medicine', 'bronx', 'genetic reasons', '’ s', '” dr.', 'nir barzilai', 'genetics. ”', 'test group', 'ashkenazi jews', 'homogeneous population', 'genetic variations', 'spot —', 'institute ’ s', 'longevity genes project', 'gene mutations', 'mrs. levy', 'high cholesterol', 'heart disease', 'alzheimer', '’ s disease']","[('last year', 'DATE'), ('The Rye Record', 'GPE'), ('112', 'CARDINAL'), ('New York State', 'GPE'), ('LongeviQuest', 'ORG'), ('a 12th decade', 'DATE'), ('Levy', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('more than 700', 'CARDINAL'), ('95', 'CARDINAL'), ('1998', 'DATE'), ('the Institute for Aging Research', 'ORG'), ('the Albert Einstein School of Medicine', 'FAC'), ('Bronx', 'GPE'), ('Nir Barzilai', 'PERSON'), ('Ashkenazi', 'NORP'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Levy', 'PERSON')]",Science
A Bottleneck on the Grid Threatens Clean Energy. New Rules Aim to Help.,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/27/climate/electric-grid-ferc-bottleneck.html,"Federal regulators on Thursday approved new rules to speed up the process for connecting wind and solar projects to the electric grid, in an attempt to reduce the growing delays that have become one of the biggest obstacles to building renewable energy in the United States.

Energy companies are investing hundreds of billions of dollars in wind farms, solar arrays and batteries, spurred on by federal tax breaks and falling costs. But these projects face a severe bottleneck: It is getting harder and taking longer to connect new power plants to the power lines that carry electricity to homes and businesses.

More than 10,000 energy projects — mostly wind, solar and batteries — were seeking permission to connect to electric grids at the end of 2022, up from 5,600 two years earlier. Grid operators have become overwhelmed by the volume. It now takes five years for the typical power plant to get approval, twice what it did a decade ago, and developers say the process has become dysfunctional.

The new rules by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, which oversees electricity markets, aim to streamline that approval process, known as the interconnection queue.",0.12138047138047137,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/28/multimedia/27cli-connect-print-zhpm/27cli-connect-zhpm-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['federal regulators', 'new rules', 'solar projects', 'electric grid', 'renewable energy', 'energy', 'solar arrays', 'federal tax', 'severe bottleneck', 'new power plants', 'power lines', 'energy projects —', 'batteries —', 'electric grids', 'grid', 'typical power plant', 'new rules', 'energy regulatory', 'oversees electricity markets', 'approval process', 'interconnection queue']","[('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('hundreds of billions of dollars', 'MONEY'), ('More than 10,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('the end of 2022', 'DATE'), ('5,600', 'CARDINAL'), ('two years earlier', 'DATE'), ('five years', 'DATE'), ('a decade ago', 'DATE'), ('the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission', 'ORG')]",Science
"A Half-Million Americans May Have Tick-Linked Meat Allergy, C.D.C. Says",https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/27/health/alpha-gal-ticks-meat-allergy.html,"When the researchers factored in this knowledge gap, they estimated that the true toll of the syndrome might be closer to a half-million, although Dr. Salzer acknowledged that the figure was “a crude estimate.”

Still, it is clear that the condition is significantly underdiagnosed, said Dr. Maya Jerath, an allergist and immunologist at Washington University in St. Louis, who has treated hundreds of patients with alpha-gal syndrome. “This is a story that every patient of mine tells me, that ‘I had to go to five physicians before they could tell me what it was,’” said Dr. Jerath, who was not involved in the new studies. “It’s nice to have numbers behind it, and it’s definitely a call to action.”

Alpha-gal syndrome, which was not formally identified until the 2000s, takes its name from galactose-alpha-1,3-galactose, a sugar present in beef, pork, lamb and the meat of most other mammals. (It is not present in humans or other apes.) Lone star ticks, which scientists believe are the primary culprits of the disease in the United States, can transmit the sugar to people through a bite. Some people’s immune systems may then label this foreign sugar a threat and overreact to its presence the next time they eat meat.

The symptoms, which often take hours to appear, are wide-ranging, and may include hives, nausea, diarrhea or anaphylactic shock. Even patients who have the syndrome may not feel sick every time they eat meat. “It’s consistently inconsistent,” Dr. Salzer said. “So this makes it a real challenge for health care providers.”

To diagnose the syndrome, clinicians can order a blood test to determine whether a patient has antibodies to alpha-gal. Until August 2021, a single commercial lab did nearly all of this antibody testing in the United States. In one of the new studies, researchers reviewed the results of the antibody tests performed at this lab from 2017 to 2022.",0.04112554112554113,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/27/multimedia/27TICKS-01-chwp/27TICKS-01-chwp-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['knowledge gap', 'true toll', 'salzer', 'crude estimate. ”', 'maya jerath', 'washington', 'louis', 'alpha-gal syndrome', '’ ”', 'jerath', 'new studies', '’ s', '’ s', 'action. ”', 'alpha-gal', 'lone', 'star ticks', 'primary culprits', 'people ’ s immune systems', 'foreign sugar', 'anaphylactic shock', '’ s', '” dr.', 'salzer', 'real challenge', 'health care providers. ”', 'blood test', 'august', 'commercial lab', 'new studies', 'antibody tests']","[('a half-million', 'CARDINAL'), ('Salzer', 'PERSON'), ('Maya Jerath', 'PERSON'), ('Washington University', 'ORG'), ('St. Louis', 'GPE'), ('hundreds', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jerath', 'PERSON'), ('Alpha', 'GPE'), ('the 2000s', 'DATE'), ('Lone', 'CARDINAL'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('hours', 'TIME'), ('Salzer', 'PERSON'), ('clinicians', 'NORP'), ('August 2021', 'DATE'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('2017', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE')]",Science
Blood of Young Mice Extends Life in the Old,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/27/health/mice-blood-aging.html,"In the 1950s, Clive McCay of Cornell University and his colleagues used parabiosis to explore aging. They joined young and old rats, stitching together their flanks so that the capillaries in their skin merged. Later, Dr. McCay and his colleagues examined the cartilage in the old rats and concluded it looked younger.

In the early 2000s, parabiosis went through a renaissance. Researchers used 21st century techniques to study what happened when animals of different ages shared the same bloodstream. They found the muscles and brains of old mice were rejuvenated, while younger mice showed signs of accelerated aging.

Some doctors jumped on these preliminary results and started offering injections of blood plasma from young people as a way to treat dementia and other diseases of old age. The Food and Drug Administration issued a warning against such treatments in 2019, cautioning that they “have no proven clinical benefits for the uses for which these clinics are advertising them and are potentially harmful.”

For several years, Dr. White and his colleagues have been tweaking parabiosis procedures in mice to better understand the anti-aging effects. The scientists joined an old and young mouse together for about three months — twice as long as typical parabiosis experiments — before carefully detaching them. After the animals recovered, the scientists observed the animals to see how much longer they lived.

The researchers not only found that the old mice lived longer, but also that the course of their aging appeared to change.",0.046604938271604945,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2023/07/27/science/27AGING/27AGING-facebookJumbo.jpg,2023,"['clive mccay', 'cornell', 'old rats', 'mccay', 'old rats', 'early 2000s', 'researchers', 'century techniques', 'different ages', 'old mice', 'preliminary results', 'offering injections', 'blood plasma', 'young people', 'old age', 'drug', 'such treatments', 'clinical benefits', 'harmful. ”', 'parabiosis procedures', 'young mouse', 'months —', 'typical parabiosis experiments —', 'old mice']","[('the 1950s', 'DATE'), ('Clive McCay of Cornell University', 'ORG'), ('McCay', 'PERSON'), ('the early 2000s', 'DATE'), ('21st century', 'DATE'), ('The Food and Drug Administration', 'ORG'), ('2019', 'DATE'), ('several years', 'DATE'), ('White', 'PERSON'), ('about three months', 'DATE')]",Science
King Charles Doesn’t Have as Many Swans as He Used to,https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/27/world/europe/uk-royal-swans.html,"Six wooden skiffs set out from the town of Sunbury-on-Thames this month on a five-day mission with a single goal: to uphold one of Britain’s more obscure royal traditions and report back to the king on how many swans he owns.

And this year, because of an outbreak of avian flu, as well as encounters with animals and aggressive humans, the numbers were not good.
